cutcaster.com 2011-06-10

# Privacy Policy | Cutcaster

We never send emails you don't opt into or share your information with outside parties.

At Cutcaster ("Cutcaster," "we," or "us"), we are deeply committed to ensuring the privacy of our customers and members and being as transparent as we can about what do, if anything, with your private information. This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes how personal information is collected from users of Cutcaster's website at www.cutcaster.com (the "Site"), and how that information is used and disclosed. By using our Site, you consent to the terms of this Policy.

 **What is Personal Information?  
** Personal information specifically identifies an individual, such as an individual's name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card or other account number, and information about that individual's activities when directly linked to him or her, such as information about his or her purchases.  
Personal information also includes demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area and preferences when such information is linked to other personal information that identifies an individual. Personal information does NOT include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data collected about a group or category of products, services or customers from which individual customer identities have been removed. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service, but no personal information will be included in the resulting data. Likewise, information about the products you purchase may be collected and combined with information about the products purchased by others. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and customer needs so that we can better consider new products and services, and tailor existing products and services to customer desires.

 **Personal Information We Collect  
** You provide personal information to us in a number of ways when you visit the Site in the future. For example, you provide us with personal information when you:  
1\. purchase photos, vectors, images or other products  
2\. participate in a survey, contest, homepage spotlight or sweepstakes on the Site  
3\. contact us by email for any reason, such as to request help with the Services, or to provide us with your comments/feedback  
4\. submit a resume to us via email or mail  
5\. post personal information in connection your Studio (e.g., in a illustratons, photo caption profile or in the metadata) or in other forums or interactive areas on the Site.  
We will collect your name, billing and shipping addresses, email address, phone number, credit card number and expiration date in this manner. We may also collect certain demographic information in connection with your participation in any survey, contest or sweepstakes on the Site.

Important Note: You have the option of telling us how you wish to be identified in connection with your videos, photos, galleries, comments and elsewhere on the Site i.e. Your Username. If you choose to use your real name (or include any personally identifying information as part of your "nickname") that information will be publicly displayed on our Site. Therefore, please use caution in determining how you wish to be identified on the Site. Additionally, when you visit our Site, some information is automatically collected, such as your computer's operating system and browser type, version, and capabilities (such as whether JavaScript is enabled and cookies are accepted), your Internet Protocol (IP) address and the time and date of your visit, the referring site (if applicable), as well as screen resolution, color and depth. This information is tracked through the use of "cookies" and "Web beacons."

Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer by your browser at the request of a web site to store your personal preferences. We use cookies to keep you logged in to the Site, to count the number of unique computers visiting the Site, and to record your user preferences. Web beacons, also known as Web bugs, are small, graphic images on a Web page or other Web-based content that allow the site owner or a third party to monitor the IP address and other information of the site or computer viewing the Web page or content. Web beacons are often invisible to the user because they are typically very small (only 1-by-1 pixel) and the same color as the background of the Web page or other Web content. Web beacons collect the IP address of the computer to which the Web beacon is sent, the URL of the page from which the Web beacon comes, and the time it was viewed. Web beacons can be linked to personal information. We may place Web beacons on the Site in conjunction with cookies to monitor how visitors are navigating and/or interacting with the Site. We treat automatically collected information as personal information if we combine it with or link it to any of the personal information identified above. Otherwise, it is used in the aggregate only. Some third parties may place cookies in advertisements and in other locations on the Site, and may place Web beacons on the Site in conjunction with such cookies. Information collected by these third parties is subject to those third parties' policies governing use and disclosure of personal information. In addition, a third-party service is used to anonymously track traffic data on the Site through the use of a cookie that is not linked to, and does not track, any personally identifiable information about users of our Site.

 **How We Use Personal Information  
** In general, we use personal information collected on the Site to provide the Services and otherwise process transactions on the Site, to provide support for the Services, to respond to user requests and inquiries, to maintain a record of our dealings with Site users, to develop new products and services and to inform users about products or services we think will be of interest. For example, we use your information to process orders of subscriptions to the Services, or purchases/downloads or other products, to communicate with you about your product purchases, your members and/or use of the Services or the Site, to provide support in response to your inquiries, to send you promotional materials via email and postal mail, to improve our products and services and to develop new products and services. When we use your personal information in our internal marketing efforts, we provide you with choices (see "Choice," below). We may also receive information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, and may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you (for example, we may receive updated information about you, such as an updated billing address, from the financial institution issuing your credit card in connection with billing for Services). If we do so, this Policy governs such information.

 **Sharing of Personal Information  
** We do NOT sell, rent or share personal information with third parties without your prior consent except in the limited circumstances described in this Policy. We may share personal information with third-party vendors who assist us in performing internal functions necessary to operate our business. These functions may include, for example, analyzing traffic information or other data, providing marketing assistance, mailing items, processing credit card transactions, and fulfilling or delivering orders. In all cases, we limit the information shared with our third-party vendors to that which is necessary to carry out those functions. We are not responsible for any additional information you provide to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them. We may also share personal information in connection with Affiliated Sites (as discussed in more detail below).  
We also disclose personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order) or with requests of law enforcement authorities; to enforce or apply this Policy or our other policies or agreements; to initiate, render, bill and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our or our customers' rights, property or safety; to protect our customers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, our Site; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay. In addition, information about our customers, including personally identifiable information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing or sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information could be transferred to third parties as one of our business assets.

 **Links to Other Web Sites  
** The Site may contain links to other Web sites. Links from our Site to other sites or content are provided for your convenience only, and we do not have control over the content or privacy and security practices and policies of such third parties or other sites. Please be careful. Any personal information you provide on linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information. We may also link to or from Web sites that are maintained by Cutcaster and/or one or more of our clients, subscribers, members or business partners or hosted by Cutcaster ("Affiliated Sites").  
When you submit personal information to Affiliated Sites you may be submitting it to both Cutcaster and/or the applicable client, subscriber or business partner. We may also share personal information we collect through Affiliated Sites with the applicable clients, subscribers and/or business partners and vice versa. For example, if you purchase prints or other products from one of our subscriber's (e.g., a professional photographer) sites maintained or hosted by Cutcaster, we may share your name and email address with such subscriber so that they may provide you with assistance or answer questions you may have in connection your purchases. In such cases, the subscriber's must agree to use such information only for the purpose for which it was provided to them by Cutcaster. Information submitted to us through Affiliated Sites will be governed by this Policy. Information you submitted to our client, subscriber or business partner through Affiliated Sites will be subject to such client's, subscriber's or business partner's privacy policy and/or practices which may differ from this Policy. We do not have control over the privacy practices of Affiliated Sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies on any Affiliated Site to which you link for information on the privacy practices of that site.

 **Use of our Site by Children  
** We encourage parents to take an active interest in their children's use of the Internet. The Site is not designed to collect information from children who are under 13 years of age, and we do not intend to collect such information. If you are under 13, you should NOT provide information on our Site. If you are under 16, you need your parents approval to upload and sell content.  
Security  
We have put into place reasonable security measures in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and alteration of information while it is under our control. We cannot, however, guarantee the protection of information against interception, misappropriation, misuse or alteration, nor can we promise that your information may be not be disclosed or accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others. Furthermore, we have no control over the security of other sites you might visit, interact with or do business with or the authenticity of the members on this site. In the Future, when you register for an account on the Site, we ask you to create a "username" and password. To protect the confidentiality of your personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of the Site by any person using your username and password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused or otherwise misappropriated.

 **Choice  
** To opt-out of receiving marketing or other promotional communications from us, or to access, change or delete your personal information maintained by us, we provide you with the following options: you may  
1) follow the "Unsubscribe" instructions contained in the communication from us;  
2) send an email to unsubscribe@cutcaster.com; or

Last Updated: January 12th, 2011  
We welcome your feedback. If you have any comments or concerns about this Policy or would like to contact us for any reason, please send an email to help@cutcaster.com
